<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Alignment | Seven Steps]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/categories/alignment/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-03T16:00:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aldric “Trevoke” Giacomoni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relaxing the Upper Body.. Aka "Drop Your Shoulders"]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2009/02/24/relaxing-the-upper-body-aka-drop-your-shoulders/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-24T15:33:42-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2009/02/24/relaxing-the-upper-body-aka-drop-your-shoulders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend of mine wrote about shoulder relaxation.. Apparently we both had the same mental block, but he solved it first &ndash; shoulder relaxation (and by extension, all relaxation) can be done up/down and &hellip; forward/back!</p>

<p>At first I didn&rsquo;t think I had that issue, my western mind automatically went &ldquo;Nah, I don&rsquo;t have that issue, my shoulders are nice and straight!&rdquo; .. And then training kicked in and the answer came : &ldquo;Well, maybe they&rsquo;re not supposed to be straight!&rdquo;
So, I let my shoulders round forward a little, which required some spinal and pelvic adjustments.. But the result is that I suddenly &lsquo;stopped feeling&rsquo; my shoulders and upper back.
For my friend, who is more advanced than I am, the effect was more drastic, and he became aware quickly of more changes, like his arms being properly connected to the body, and feeling better rooted in spite of not having his legs bent as much.
I&rsquo;m still playing with the feeling, the muscles around my spine don&rsquo;t know what to do with this weight, I think.. I&rsquo;ve got to work on this some more ;&ndash;)
Still, this is a good discovery.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solved My Left Shoulder Pain?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2008/04/15/solved-my-left-shoulder-pain/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-15T11:21:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2008/04/15/solved-my-left-shoulder-pain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is it a worrying trend that I write mostly about pain in here? :)</p>

<p>Every once in a while, usually while doing a high block with my left arm, I&rsquo;d feel a pain in my left shoulder. It felt like a part was rolling over another one.. Muscle over bone, or something like that. It&rsquo;s not pleasant and is the kind of pain that stops your movement quite short and quite abruptly.</p>

<p>It happened yesterday while doing an uppercut (or, you know, punch to under the jaw/to the throat/etc). I realized my body alignment was wrong and my left elbow wasn&rsquo;t kept in properly. As soon as I fix that, I think, I&rsquo;ll feel a lot better about the whole thing :)</p>

<p>This of course begs the question.. What else am I not aligning properly, but maybe not quite wrong enough to get pain from it?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
