<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | Seven Steps]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-06T23:37:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aldric “Trevoke” Giacomoni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AT&T: A Ten-year Customer Says Goodbye]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2011/05/10/att-a-ten-year-customer-says-goodbye/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-10T22:13:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2011/05/10/att-a-ten-year-customer-says-goodbye</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just moved into a new apartment where the AT&amp;T reception is, well, atrocious. Still, I like AT&amp;T, so I&rsquo;m dragging my feet to switch to Verizon (or something else).</p>

<p>Today, I spoke in live chat to some AT&amp;T employee. I believe the name was Monica Garnett but I could be wrong &mdash; and it probably doesn&rsquo;t matter. My issue was that I didn&rsquo;t seem to have a mailbox for my phone number. She says my data plan is unsupported for smart phones.</p>

<p>&hellip; Wait, what? I&rsquo;ve been using this data plan for over a year with this phone. Maybe I never got voicemail, but who cares! It WORKED. I had unlimited text and unlimited data. Now, yes, I know, this plan had been removed and AT&amp;T wasn&rsquo;t offering it anymore, but I am an existing customer, I get the perk of keeping that, right?</p>

<p>&hellip; No. I was told I could switch to their 200Mb/month or 2Gb/month plan, which I did, but what I wasn&rsquo;t told is that THESE PLANS DO NOT INCLUDE MESSAGING.</p>

<p>Now, I want to fix this. I got screwed by a company, big whoop, whatever, I&rsquo;ll just limit myself a little. THE WEBSITE DOES NOT GIVE ME REASONABLE OPTIONS. I can get unlimited text, or unlimited text with any mobile-to-mobile calling, or 1000 texts.</p>

<p>I could pay $15 for 200 megs and $10 for 1000 texts, and then I&rsquo;d have $25 &mdash; which is, $5 less than unlimited data and unlimited texts. Huh. NO.</p>

<p>I could pay $25 for 2Gb and $10 for 1000 texts, or $20 for unlimited texts. So .. $35 or $45? NO.</p>

<p>Seriously? So I have to pay MORE now to have LESS than I used to have? Well, goodbye, AT&amp;T. Guess who&rsquo;s going to go say hi to another phone service provider tomorrow?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scrivener for Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2011/02/05/scrivener-for-linux/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-05T14:09:34-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2011/02/05/scrivener-for-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a title="Scrivener" href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php" target="_blank">Scrivener</a> is a wonderful OSX app for writing basically anything you want (novels, plays, theses, etc). There&rsquo;s a beta out for Windows. As it turns out, they&rsquo;re actually developing it using the Qt toolkit.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivenerforwindows/" target="_blank">Windows Beta</a> runs on WINE, if you do a bit of work. I am getting all my information from a Lifehacker tip, just rewriting it and adding some more information for those who don&rsquo;t know enough.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Install <a title="WINE Is Not an Emulator" href="http://www.winehq.org/" target="_blank">WINE</a> -- version 1.3.5 or higher.</li>
    <li>Download <a title="Winetricks" href="http://wiki.winehq.org/winetricks" target="_blank">winetricks</a>.  [code]$ wget http://winetricks.org/winetricks[/code]</li>
    <li>I also recommend installing the 'cabextract' tool, as indicated in the previous link.</li>
    <li>run winetricks and install the following runtime libraries: [code]$ sh winetricks vcrun2008 vcrun6 quartz dotnet20[/code]</li>
    <li>I did not need to do this, but the link also recommends downloading qsvg.dll and qtsvg.dll and copying them to your ~/.wine/drive_c/windows/system32 directory. I'm not actually sure where to find these, and installing Scrivener created a qsvg4.dll file.</li>
    <li>Finally, install and run the Beta.</li>
</ul>


<p>Let me know if you run into any issues following these instructions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poulsbo + Xorg 1.7 = (Hope You Like Downgrading)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/05/11/poulsbo-xorg-1-7-hope-you-like-downgrading/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-11T15:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/05/11/poulsbo-xorg-1-7-hope-you-like-downgrading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you happen to use Gentoo on a Notebook, you may already know this. If not..</p>

<p>At the time of this writing, If you have a Poulsbo video card (another craptastic Intel invention) do <em>not</em> upgrade to xorg-server 1.7. Stay on 1.6.5-r1 or whatever you have. If you upgrade, xorg will just refuse to work for you, and downgrading is kind of a pain.</p>

<p>If you have upgraded already, then here&rsquo;s what to do:</p>

<p><a href="http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=290679#c4">http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=290679#c4</a></p>

<p>After doing this, you&rsquo;ll need to also mask &gt;xorg-server-1.6.5-r1, then re-install the old xorg-server, and finally re-emerge everything you have installed from the category x11-drivers.</p>

<p>Have fun!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Github's Customer Service: Bad Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/03/12/githubs-customer-service-bad-review/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-12T09:39:28-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/03/12/githubs-customer-service-bad-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will readily admit that I don&rsquo;t know all that much about Github or Git for that matter. I use them, they&rsquo;re handy, and that&rsquo;s where it stops. I read about a git feature called &ldquo;smart HTTP&rdquo;, which would allow to communicate both ways with git (push and pull) with HTTP or HTTPS. So, I asked Github about it &ndash; it would be nice for them to have this feature, because I currently can&rsquo;t push to Github from work. Here&rsquo;s how the exchange went.
(this first message is from memory, as I used the web interface, so I don&rsquo;t have a copy of it)
<strong>Me:</strong> <em>
Hi, I just read about this: <a href="http://progit.org/2010/03/04/smart-http.html">http://progit.org/2010/03/04/smart-http.html</a> and I would like to know when Github plans on implementing this, because it would be very useful.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>From: Tekkub (Support staff)
Subject: [Contact] Upgrading git to support smart HTTP ?</strong></em></p>

<p>You do know that Scott (the guy who wrote Pro Git) works for us, right?  We&rsquo;re well
aware of smart http&hellip;<em></p>

<hr />

<p></em><em>I tried to make light of the condescending tone and sent the following reply:</em>
<strong>Me: </strong>
Nope.. Had no idea.
So when will it be implemented? ;)</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>From: Tekkub (Support staff)
Subject: [Contact] Upgrading git to support smart HTTP ?</strong></p>

<p>It will be implemented when it is&hellip;</p>

<hr />

<p>That&rsquo;s when I just gave up. I don&rsquo;t know if whoever handles the messages is paid or not, but I&rsquo;m pretty sure Github pays its employees by now. I&rsquo;m using a free account, so they wouldn&rsquo;t lose anything by me leaving them, and they do provide a great service.
Am I just being picky when I expect the support staff to be polite? I say this as someone who has worked as support staff for over three years: no. The support staff SHOULD, nay, MUST be polite. I don&rsquo;t care how flat your company hierarchy is, I don&rsquo;t care how young or forward-thinking the company is, and I especially don&rsquo;t care if your target audience is Asperger&rsquo;s syndrome-suffering programmers who laugh at Star Trek jokes and read slash fiction. You&rsquo;re the support, you&rsquo;re polite. Especially over a medium like text, where you can&rsquo;t easily place a slap on the shoulder, a grin and a wink.</p>

<p>This has left a bad taste in my mouth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gentoo on a Dell Inspiron Mini 10]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/03/01/gentoo-on-a-dell-inspiron-mini-10/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-01T11:06:11-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/03/01/gentoo-on-a-dell-inspiron-mini-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are a few gotchas:
1) If you have a SSD drive, you need to <em>modprobe pata_sch</em> to see it.
2) when using GRUB, install it on whatever drive the hard drive is, even if it&rsquo;s /dev/sdc &mdash; and let your FSTAB use /dev/sda. Chances are that /dev/sda is your liveUSB.
3) In the kernel, in the I2C options, don&rsquo;t let it pick automatically &ndash; instead, select the algorithm options in the menu that appears (I don&rsquo;t know it off-hand, will edit this post later to add the important information). This will allow you to install the kernel driver for the poulsbo card (kmod-psb, I believe).</p>

<p>For the rest, so far, it seems that the howto on the Gentoo wiki is good. I installed e17 very painlessly.</p>

<p>Wireless was a bit trickier.
I needed to use gentoo-sources-2.6.33, which at the time of this writing was masked as ~x86. A big advantage though is that it has support for the Atom processor (and the proper driver for the broadcom card!).
Enable the &ldquo;B43&rdquo; driver in the kernel.
Then, follow the instructions given <a href="http://linuxwireless.org/en/users/Drivers/b43#fw-b43-lp">here</a>:</p>

<blockquote>git clone http://git.bu3sch.de/git/b43-tools.git
cd b43-tools/fwcutter
make
cd ..
</blockquote>


<p>Use version 4.174.64.19 of Broadcom&rsquo;s proprietary driver. (The tarball is mislabeled as &ldquo;4.178.10.4&rdquo;, but it is actually 4.174.64.19.)
Download and extract the firmware from this driver tarball (Gentoo&rsquo;s installation directory for this is /lib/firmware):</p>

<blockquote>export FIRMWARE_INSTALL_DIR="/lib/firmware"
wget http://downloads.openwrt.org/sources/broadcom-wl-4.178.10.4.tar.bz2
tar xjf broadcom-wl-4.178.10.4.tar.bz2
cd broadcom-wl-4.178.10.4/linux
sudo ../../fwcutter/b43-fwcutter -w "$FIRMWARE_INSTALL_DIR" wl_apsta.o
</blockquote>


<p>At the time of this writing, although the b43-firmware is available and promises to give us what we need, the b43-fwcutter tool is only at version 12, and not 13, so it can&rsquo;t be used. This is why we need to use <em>git</em> to download the latest version and correctly build the firmware by hand.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
