<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Martial Arts | Seven Steps]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/categories/martial-arts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-06T23:37:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aldric “Trevoke” Giacomoni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shu Ha Ri and Evolution of a Skill]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2014/02/18/shu-ha-ri-and-evolution-of-a-skill/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-18T15:17:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2014/02/18/shu-ha-ri-and-evolution-of-a-skill</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shu Ha Ri comes from the world of Japanese Noh theater, and has been since attached to the world of martial arts and <a title="Alistair Cockburn's words on Shu Ha Ri" href="http://alistair.cockburn.us/Shu+Ha+Ri">Agile development</a>. Roughly, &ldquo;shu ha ri&rdquo; means &ldquo;learn / detach / transcend&rdquo;. The link has some words about that meaning. I&rsquo;d like to talk about my particular take on Shu Ha Ri, which came out of a parking-lot conversation with a martial arts teacher friend of mine:</p>

<ol>
    <li>Shu. Do the damn technique.</li>
    <li>Ha. Vary the damn technique.</li>
    <li>Ri. You don't need the damn technique.</li>
</ol>


<p>And here is the slightly longer interpretation.</p>

<p>SHU: right foot in front, grab the left wrist from the front with the right hand. Study the particular wrist escape that has been taught in this situation. In Agile words: be rigorous about your Agile practice. Do it &ldquo;dumbly&rdquo; until you get good at it and everyone in your team is OK with it.</p>

<p>HA: grab some wrist in some way, and play with that wrist escape. Add footwork. See what works and what doesn&rsquo;t. In Agile words, now&rsquo;s the time to see when is a good time for standup, what should be said, how long the standup should take. Or maybe change the beginning of the iteration; or how you do story breakdown. Pick ONE variable, change it, and learn from what happened, whether it worked or it didn&rsquo;t (&ldquo;worked&rdquo; is a variable term, at this point of your growth, you&rsquo;ll know it well enough when you see it).</p>

<p>RI: It&rsquo;s not about a wrist grab anymore, but about much more fundamental principles. Detached from the technique, or the labels of &ldquo;wrist grab&rdquo; and &ldquo;wrist escape&rdquo;, it simply becomes about the right movement producing the right result (&ldquo;right&rdquo; is a variable term, at this point of your growth, you&rsquo;ll know it without seeing it). In Agile words, you understand why a standup is just one example of a practical application of the Agile principles, and you are able to create custom applications of the principle for your teams, so that they can be Agile in the way that works best for them.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>You may notice that HA and RI seem just a little similar from the point of vagueness: you&rsquo;ll know it when you see it. It takes a long time to work through HA, and the line between the two is fairly definite, but hard to find. So practice, practice, practice. Or rather, perfect practice, perfect practice, perfect practice. And check your ego at the door.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sparring]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2013/05/15/sparring/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-15T21:05:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2013/05/15/sparring</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>What Sparring Is</h1>


<p>Sparring is a playful and explorative interaction.</p>

<p>Sparring is an exercise, a drill. The Japanese use the word KUMITE &ndash; which basically means &ldquo;grouped hands&rdquo; or &ldquo;pair hands&rdquo;, &ldquo;joined hands&rdquo;, &ldquo;hands together&rdquo; (the Wikipedia article suggests &ldquo;grappling hands&rdquo;).</p>

<p>Sparring is a two-person free-form exercise wherein you get to examine scenarios involving combinations, footwork, distancing, rhythm, controlled power, and focus to improve yourself and your partner.</p>

<p><a id="more"></a><a id="more-355"></a></p>

<p><strong>Combinations</strong>: you get to play first-hand with things you have learned and put them in an environment where there is no set response. You learn what the combination does and what it does not do. You get a feel for when to use it, when not to use it. You will also learn not to stop after a single strike. WOOHOO you got a strike in! So what? Get in another one and another one! Learn how to use feints and setups for your combinations.</p>

<p><strong>Footwork</strong>: sliding along a line, stepping around. When to change your front foot, when not to. When to step, when not to. This is harder than it sounds when you only have a split-second to make the decision.</p>

<p><strong>Distancing</strong>: You can draw two concentric circles around an immobile person, representing the reach of their arms and legs. You learn how far your strikes go depending on your stance, you learn when the opponent is entering your zone and when they&rsquo;re dancing just outside of it. You learn where your partner&rsquo;s zone is. You will learn to enter and leave the opponent&rsquo;s zone, <em>and when to do so</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Rhythm</strong>: people have a rhythm (let&rsquo;s leave the no-rhythm stepping of the Fremen out of this for a second). Controlling the fight can be done by means of controlling this rhythm. Anything you do between those beats is either invisible or unavoidable to the person. Someone who is jumping up and down is most vulnerable right before they land. Someone who takes a step forward is vulnerable when they are transferring the weight to the foot if it&rsquo;s still up in the air.</p>

<p><strong>Power</strong>: sparring is not about power generation, because unless your partner is much better than you are, you&rsquo;re eventually going to hurt your partner, and they&rsquo;re not going to want to train with you again, which probably defeats the whole purpose, because when you run out of training partners, you&rsquo;ve got no one to spar with. If both players have a solid understanding and agreement, then you CAN use power. I&rsquo;ve been in a few very fun sparring matches like that, very exhilarating experiences where the speed and the power was way up. Because both of us were playing and exploring, and we had a clear agreement and understanding on the goal of the drill, it was fine. You can and should develop power &ndash; however, this is done with other drills.</p>

<p><strong>Focus</strong>: Alright, so we are not going to use full power. <strong>We&rsquo;re still going to throw quick and precise strikes and we&rsquo;re still going to make solid contact.</strong> While we&rsquo;re not doing point-sparring, we&rsquo;re still sparring, and a solid strike counts as a strike that could have been much more powerful; in proper point sparring, that&rsquo;s a point &ndash; not touching someone with your toe. So, you should always honor the strike as being a real strike if it had the proper focus/kime, etc. It&rsquo;s of course OK to smack down a round-house that made contact weakly, because it would have just been a touch. That is part of the contract. &lsquo;Contact&rsquo; does not mean &lsquo;hit&rsquo; if it does not have focus.</p>

<p>Now, having said all this, full-contact sparring has all the same things, but they don&rsquo;t limit the power. <strong>Full-contact, full-speed sparring is practiced in systems where significant body conditioning occurs. This is not a coincidence.</strong></p>

<h1>What Sparring Is Not</h1>


<div>Sparring is not a fight. Sparring is not a competition. If you or your partner try to win, then the purpose of the drill is defeated.</div>


<p>If you consider sparring to be a practice fight, then all of a sudden it&rsquo;s OK to hurt someone &ndash; because that&rsquo;s what you&rsquo;re practicing. Sure, it&rsquo;s not knitting class, but sparring is not about hurting someone. And it&rsquo;s not about winning.</p>

<p>Why are we wearing gloves? Headgear? A mouthpiece?  These aren&rsquo;t excuses to hit someone harder. They are there to protect YOUR body, not the opponent&rsquo;s. They are worn by both people because you are training something dangerous, in which mistakes happen. The Pavlovian response to putting on gloves should not be &ldquo;Yeah! Time to waste something!&rdquo;, it should be &ldquo;Time to make sure I am fully alert.&rdquo;</p>

<p>There are two excellent articles coming from the world of the Russian martial art called Systema. The first is called <a title="The Kickboxing Trap" href="http://russianmartialart.org/ikfkicktrap.html" target="_blank">The Kickboxing Trap</a>. It talks about the following three traps:</p>

<ol>
    <li><em>Trying NOT to lose</em> (which is not exactly trying to win, but equally dangerous and much more subtle)</li>
    <li><em>Trying to move faster than the opponent </em>(in Systema, sparring is done at a slower speed)</li>
    <li><em>Having undefined goals</em> (WHY are you sparring? Which aspect of your practice are you working on improving?)</li>
</ol>


<p>You should go read it.</p>

<p>The second article is called <a title="Slow Sparring Game of Russian Martial Arts" href="http://www.dojoofthefourwinds.com/sparring.html" target="_blank">Slow Sparring Game Of Russian Martial Arts</a>. I will give an excerpt here to give you an idea of a particular and very effective method of sparring (I know this from experience). In the following excerpt, emphasis is mine.</p>

<blockquote>The basic premise of the Slow Sparring Game (SSG) is <strong>to create an environment where all technical aspects of hand to hand combat can be explored in relative safety</strong>, while providing the body a chance to execute and cultivate true spontaneity. To facilitate this, the <strong>SSG must be viewed as a slow motion representation of combat</strong>.</blockquote>


<p>Here are some things it talks about:</p>

<ol>
    <li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Changing speed, whether speeding up or slowing down during the movement</span></li>
    <li>Changing trajectory, just because you can when you're going slow</li>
    <li>The defender moving faster than the attacker</li>
</ol>


<p>You should go read it.</p>

<div></div>


<div>
<h1>How to get good at sparring</h1>
There's no secret, no magic formula. You gotta spar. <strong>You have to spar while being fully alert and cognizant of all those things</strong>. What if you've learned to spar already, but what you really learned was how to beat down (or how to be afraid of the other person) ? Then you have to spend time being extra-aware, with partners who will be understanding, and you probably should slow down even more than you otherwise would, because I can guarantee you from experience that you'll speed up, because you'll get afraid or uncomfortable or angry or competitive. It happens. And it's nothing to be ashamed about. People make mistakes. We all do. But you have to be in there with the intent of improving and helping your partner improve, with an open mind.
<h1>What if someone breaks the agreement?</h1>
This, for better or for worse, depends on the culture in your environment.

If they break the agreement because they are trying to fix their habits, be patient, take breaks, talk to them. Be aware of when they get scared or uncomfortable and ease up on the pressure.

If they break the agreement because they don't believe in it, then I would say, don't spar with them. Have them read this blog post and have a conversation with them about it. Send them to a Systema school for a little while so they learn that speed and power aren't the main elements in a fight. Or, if you're much better than they are, let them get frustrated and angry and beat themselves against the wall. Eventually they'll get tired of fighting. Every once in a while, people meet a problem and they have to burn all their Yang before they realize that it's easier to be Yin.
<h1>Other Valuable Information</h1>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Teacher-student relationships when sparring</h2>
Sparring can be a very effective teaching tool: you can give students the proper positive feedback for a good strike, and the proper feedback (or lack thereof) for an improper strike. You can teach them to find openings, to think in circles (or spheres), to recognize rhythm. And if you're really good - you'll do it without speaking. You can choose to interrupt the sparring regularly to examine the current situation at more leisure. Sometimes it's necessary to slow things down.
<h2>Differences in experience levels</h2>
<em>The more-experienced player should only ever answer with 80% of the power of the less-experienced player.</em> The more-experienced player should not be punishing or otherwise bullying the lower-experienced player. There are further lessons to be learned there by the more-experienced player, which I will not discuss here, because it might be a spoiler, and some of this stuff you really should learn by doing.
<h2>What not to learn from watching high-experience players</h2>
Higher-experience people who are sparring together may seem to be ignoring such strikes, most likely because they're working on other things, like the focus, the rhythm, the continuity of motion, etc., it does not mean it is OK to ignore these strikes. They are (or should be) acknowledging the strikes, storing the experience in memory to learn from it later, and continuing.
<h1>Conclusion</h1>
Sparring is, or should be, a very enjoyable activity. It is a time where you can learn much about yourself and about your opponent (cue <a title="Seraph vs. Neo" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;v=TDhLXkRhg60#t=90s" target="_blank">Matrix reference</a> - I was the only one laughing in the theater when this happened...). It is a time where you drop all pretenses, drop your ego, and just get to be, along with your partner. My best friends are my best sparring partners, and this is not a coincidence.

Proper sparring requires a set of agreements between all parties, and tremendous mindfulness. Thankfully, the payoffs are huge. With proper sparring, you will grow intellectually and emotionally and, if that's not enough for you, your martial skills will also improve

Much can be learned during sparring. Usually after the fact. I can think of a handful of occasions where something happened and, during a pause, one of us said "Oh, that move came from kata X" or "I've been practicing Y and I had no idea what it was for - now I do!"

So, to steal unashamedly from a great man... <a title="UnderstandGoodPlay - the book" href="http://www.bushinbooks.com/about.html" target="_blank">Understand? Good. Play!</a>

</div>


<p>Collapse this post</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[School Creed]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2013/04/27/school-creed/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-27T19:58:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2013/04/27/school-creed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the dojo where I spent my formative years as a martial artist, there is a school creed. A quick search online has revealed that many schools have a similar creed. Every class says it as we begin, after bowing in, before calisthenics. I hear it and/or say it about three times per dojo night.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a simple creed, and clearly not unique. Here&rsquo;s what it says:</p>

<blockquote>I intend to develop myself in a positive manner
and avoid anything that would reduce my mental
growth or physical health.
I intend to develop self-discipline, in order to
bring out the best in myself and others.
I intend to use what I learn in class
constructively and defensively, to help myself
and others and never be abusive or offensive.

&nbsp;</blockquote>


<p>Kids and adults alike learn this creed and repeat it, together. All are taught to pronounce it powerfully, in the manner of an assertion. In that way, it is very similar to the few sentences American children have to repeat in their schools at the beginning of each day, and which sickened me for how similar it was to unadulterated brainwashing. Speaking of which, <a title="The Kafka Shuffle" href="http://the-programmers-stone.com/2008/01/05/the-kafka-shuffle/">this</a> is a very interesting and potentially disturbing read on the reading materials in school, but I digress.</p>

<p>Why do we make people repeat these words? We sometimes ask kids if they know what some words in there mean, like self-discipline. But certainly we&rsquo;re not teaching vocabulary to adults. So what&rsquo;s the point?</p>

<p>Well, the point is practice. These sentences are to be pronounced not only as assertions, but mindfully, pronouncing your desire to grow in that direction. They are simple precepts:</p>

<ol>
    <li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Always aim for the things in life that will allow you to grow, always avoid the things that will make you shrink. Trick: sometimes you have to shrink in order to grow. Are those decisions mistakes? Are they following this code?</span></li>
    <li>Always try to be the best you can be, always try to allow others around you to be the best they can be. Trick: can you do both at the same time? Do you sometimes have to not be the best you can be to prod people into being the best they can be?</li>
    <li>What you are learning martially is meant for good. Possibly along the path of the Life-Giving Sword, but not necessarily. Simple application: don't get into bar fights. Trick application: everything you do must come from Love.</li>
</ol>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is intentionally left a little vague. Find your own questions. I&rsquo;ll answer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Schism in Martial Training Paradigms]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2012/06/19/the-schism-in-martial-training-paradigms/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-19T21:52:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2012/06/19/the-schism-in-martial-training-paradigms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>You're training wrong! No, YOU're training wrong!</h2>


<p>A recent set of conversations have led me to examine the major difference in martial training. I&rsquo;m going to start by separating training in two categories, making an imperfect black-and-white model of the martial world:</p>

<ul>
    <li>Traditional eastern training</li>
    <li>Jeet Kune Do-like training</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, let&rsquo;s start to talk about the <em><strong>PURPOSE</strong></em><strong><em> </em></strong>of each, in a fairly roundabout way.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about the traditional drill which has become sort of a standard: &ldquo;Grab my wrist&rdquo;. The joint lock. Many people have images of rows of people in white uniforms with colored belts, all standing there, grabbing one of their partner&rsquo;s wrists, and waiting. Then the partner tries to do some kind of fancy something-or-other and ideally, the person grabbing the wrist is now very sorry for themselves.</p>

<p>Well, there&rsquo;s a clear problem with that drill, isn&rsquo;t there? In fact, there&rsquo;s a LOT of problems. Let&rsquo;s talk about them.</p>

<h2>1. Who in their right mind would grab someone's wrist?</h2>


<p>Okay, good point. You win. It&rsquo;s a silly drill. No, but seriously &ndash; superficially, that&rsquo;s dumb, unless maybe you were trying to take some weaker person away with you &ndash; and in that case, you&rsquo;d also want to make sure they weren&rsquo;t making sound. So, why grab someone&rsquo;s wrist?</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s look at it a little differently. People use their hands often, every day, for a number of fairly varied tasks. They use their hands with purpose, like grabbing a mug, drinking from it, driving, texting, typing on a keyboard, opening a door&hellip; People are used to relating to the world through their hands. It is more natural than, say, lying down on the ground and trying to get a knee or ankle lock on someone with both of your feet, so it is an easier starting point. So there&rsquo;s the grabbing part.</p>

<p>Why the wrist? Well, actually, use the exact same argument as the last paragraph. People relate better to what they feel near their hands, they already have a relatively solid mind-body connection there, so new movements can be put together with fewer mental leaps. You can feel the resistance, in any direction, more easily. You can &lsquo;listen&rsquo; more easily with your hands than, as a beginner, you can with other, bigger, less-trained muscles.</p>

<h2>2. Why grab someone's wrist and let them do whatever they want?</h2>


<p>Yeah, I mean, why? They&rsquo;re gonna start moving your hand, arm, wrist, elbow, shoulder, body, this way and that, and you&rsquo;re just gonna let it happen? What kind of an idiot are you?</p>

<p>Well, for starters, as the person portraying the &lsquo;attacker&rsquo;, it is not currently your role to beat up the other person. See, they are the receiver, so it is their turn to practice, with comfortable slowness and smoothness, a potentially complex move which may require subtle manipulation (moving the body in just the right way to get the desired result). So you should let them experiment until they are comfortable with the move. That&rsquo;s the whole point. Maybe now is a good time to explain why people need to get comfortable &ndash; the stuff that you&rsquo;re practicing actually can hurt you. I know, kind of a shocker, right? Performed improperly, on an opponent that is trying to resist, forcing to try and get the desired result, one can truly do long-lasting damage to a partner. The point of a partner is to train with them for a long time, so this defeats the purpose a bit.</p>

<h2>3. Why grab someone's wrist and not have a follow-up move?</h2>


<p>I hear this all the time: if you&rsquo;re grabbing someone, you&rsquo;re probably pulling them into a punch with the other hand &ndash; or worse (knife, whatever). Yes. Great. Not for beginner practice. The previous point applies &ndash; people need to get comfortable with what they&rsquo;re doing FIRST.  Follow-up moves start to play with intermediate-to-advanced concepts which should only be brought in later, when both people have an understanding of when one has failed to apply the technique, so no useless forcing happens. Some of these concepts are stepping, angles, combinations,  directional shifts</p>

<h2>4. Why stay locked when they have a lock on you?</h2>


<p>This fourth point is a little subtle: locks are dynamic things. If someone puts you in a lock and they stop applying force in some direction, then you can move out of the lock. And again,</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Okay, so I waxed lyrical about the fact that the wrist grab is a beginner&rsquo;s move. Oh wait, no, I didn&rsquo;t. Hang on a sec.. What I said was that the most basic way of practicing the wrist grab, the safest way, the way that leads to growth, BASED ON THE TRADITIONAL TRAINING SYSTEM, is a static exercise, removing most of the variables of combat.</p>

<p>Yeah&hellip; And then what? Well, once you&rsquo;re comfortable with static, you begin to add energy to it, and that&rsquo;s when it truly comes alive. Pull, push, add a strike, add a step.. All those things get practiced until the student is comfortable. And then what? Are you gonna start sparring and suddenly grab someone&rsquo;s wrist? Well&hellip; Probably not. You&rsquo;d probably end up getting punched in the face, and you&rsquo;d deserve it, too.</p>

<p>The neat thing about this practice is that it teaches you to feel how someone else applies their force in a direction (for which I will use the word &lsquo;energy&rsquo; from now on). The tricky thing about this practice is that it only works by surprise. And the hard thing about it is that you can really mess up someone&rsquo;s body if you do it suddenly enough.</p>

<p>Yeah.. But wait! I just said you weren&rsquo;t gonna do it when sparring! Well, no, you&rsquo;re not. But if you are going to do it, someone will have grabbed you &mdash; or sent energy in some shape in your direction (e.g. a punch), and that will be your answer. It will be swift, it will be sudden, and with the correct precision, it will send the poor sod on the floor. And what if it fails? Well, you can run, you can try to hit the guy a lot, or you could go for the subtler option, which requires more years of training &ndash; switch to another lock on the next available joint.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Okay, now I bet you&rsquo;re saying that I&rsquo;m just giving you the runaround. I talked about purpose, somewhere way above, and I haven&rsquo;t mentioned anything about it since! That&rsquo;s true. But I was also setting up the stage. What is the purpose of the traditional training? The purpose of traditional training is <strong>NOT</strong> to make you an efficient fighter <strong>QUICKLY</strong>. Traditional training should be making you look inward and discover the connection between your mind and body, helping you discover who you really are and what your illusions are. As the training progresses, it gets increasingly hard and subtle, therefore refining you and your understanding of your place in society through the study of conflict.</p>

<p>Gosh, so many big words. How much what I just said is true? Eh&hellip; Nowadays, it depends on the student.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Someone I was talking to recently compared &ldquo;grab the wrist&rdquo; to &ldquo;we can both throw jabs and our only defense is slipping&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Well, let&rsquo;s apply the same concepts &ndash; though I won&rsquo;t make as big a deal of them since you saw them above.</p>

<p>1) Why would you just jab? Well, why not. Maybe you can knock the guy out, or explode his nose, or just jab four times before he realizes you&rsquo;re taking the initiative / preempting. It&rsquo;s a strike and it&rsquo;s got chances to be effective. Besides, throwing multiple jabs is a good drill to build up your shoulder muscles and practice targeted striking!</p>

<p>2) Why jab and let them do whatever they want? Well.. Alright, in this drill, we&rsquo;re not. We jab and they only get to slip. This is a strict drill, working hips, legs, maybe stepping, maybe parrying with the hands. This is all good stuff.</p>

<p>3) Why jab and not have a follow-up move? Well, because it&rsquo;s a drill, duh! We&rsquo;re just doing this over and over, working on very specific skills that directly and obviously relate to what I call a level one confrontation: strikes. Hell, it&rsquo;s worked for boxers. Nah.. This analogy is flawed. Boxers don&rsquo;t use their legs for anything but power generation. No kicks, no trips.</p>

<p>4) Why not counter when you slip? Well.. That would end the drill, and it&rsquo;s not the point. You&rsquo;d have a drill for counters. These drills are, of course, just as artificial as &ldquo;grab my wrist&rdquo;. The thing is, some people like them better. They need to move.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>In general, I&rsquo;ve found the camp to be split between people who prefer the &ldquo;grab my wrist&rdquo; context and people who prefer &ldquo;jab and slip&rdquo;. Both drills get practiced by both people, colored by the environment, but one side matches their personality better. &ldquo;Grab my wrist&rdquo; is not realistic! They say. &ldquo;Jab and slip&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t develop your sensitivity! They say.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what one guy had to say about it.. You may have heard of him, his name is Bruce Lee, and he wrote that book called &ldquo;Tao of Jeet Kune Do&rdquo;:</p>

<blockquote>"Instead of facing combat in its suchness, then, most systems of martial art accumulate a "fancy mess" that distorts and cramps their practitioners and distracts them from the actual reality of combat, which is simple and direct. Instead of going immediately to the heart of things, flowery forms (organized despair) and artificial techniques are ritualistically practiced to simulate actual combat. Thus, instead of 'being' in combat these practitioners are 'doing' something 'about' combat.
"Worse still, super mental power and spiritual this and spiritual that are desperately incorporated until these practitioners drift further and further into mystery and abstraction. All such things are futile attempts to arrest and fix the ever-changing movements in combat and to dissect and analyze them like a corpse." (p. 14)
"Forms are vain repetitions which offer an orderly and beautiful escape from self-knowledge with an alive opponent." (p. 16)</blockquote>


<p>While I agree with some of it, I think there is a fundamental flaw in trying to reject such static training: it develops a fundamental and critical awareness and sensitivity which becomes reflexive over time. I&rsquo;ve watched a 70+ year-old man move another guy around like a volley ball with impressive speed and precision, and his training had been extremely traditional (though, granted, over a period of fifty years or more).</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>I think that when people criticize a drill, they&rsquo;re really criticizing instructors who have no understanding of the depth of the drill &ndash; or, reflexively, criticizing themselves for not having a deep enough understanding of the drill, an unwillingness to practice. <em>No think. No talk. Train.</em></p>

<p>On that note, I stop my tongue-fu.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nidan Test]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/03/19/nidan-test/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-19T12:33:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/03/19/nidan-test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On February 28th, 2010, I took the test to become a second-degree black belt.</p>

<p>Here is a summary of what I had to do, besides the calisthenics:</p>

<ul>
    <li>All my empty-hand forms, opposite side. There are eight of them. This meant that if the first step was with the left foot, I had to do it with the right foot. I suppose you could also call that 'mirror'. The names are : seisan, seiuchin, naihanchi, wonsu, chinto, kusanku, sunsu, and sanchin. I admit we did not do sanchin opposite side, but that's not too surprising. It's not a complex form, but there's nothing to be gained from being able to do it regular and opposite side.</li>
    <li>My first weapon form, opposite side. This is a bo (long staff) form. The name is tokumine no kun.</li>
    <li>My third weapon form. This is a bo form. The name is urashi bo (sometimes called urashi no kun).</li>
    <li>My fourth weapon form. This is a sai form. the name is chatan yara no sai.</li>
    <li>The fifth weapon form. Note that I said "The" and not "My" ... Because I hadn't learned it. I was told to stay with the group and keep up. I did. That is my proud moment. :) It is a tonfa form. The name is hamahiga no tonfa.</li>
    <li>Self-defense, including bunkai (analysis) from the various empty-hand forms.</li>
    <li>Knife defenses</li>
    <li>Sparring. This was actually rather fun, about thirty people in line and we (everyone testing for nidan) fought them one after another.</li>
</ul>


<p>It was tough, but it was mostly a mind exercise. I must admit not remembering any thoughts or feelings during the test; I heard the instructions and executed them, and waited for the next instructions.</p>

<p>I passed.</p>

<p>Phew.</p>

<p>Alright, let&rsquo;s work towards the next steps.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
