<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Funny | Seven Steps]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/categories/funny/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-06T23:37:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aldric “Trevoke” Giacomoni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Country Alert Levels #funny]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/01/20/country-alert-levels-funny/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-20T12:39:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2010/01/20/country-alert-levels-funny</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s break the monotony with something funny:</p>

<p>The English are feeling the pinch in relation to recent terrorist threats? and have raised their security level from &ldquo;Miffed&rdquo; to &ldquo;Peeved.&rdquo; Soon, ?though, security levels may be raised yet again to &ldquo;Irritated&rdquo; or even &ldquo;A? Bit Cross.&rdquo; The English have not been &ldquo;A Bit Cross&rdquo; since the blitz in 1940 ?when tea supplies all but ran out.</p>

<p>Terrorists have been re-categorized from ?&ldquo;Tiresome&rdquo; to a &ldquo;Bloody Nuisance.&rdquo; The last time the British issued a? &ldquo;Bloody Nuisance&rdquo; warning level was in 1588 when threatened by the Spanish Armada.??</p>

<p>The Scots raised their threat level from &ldquo;Pissed Off&rdquo; to &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s get the? Bastards&rdquo; They don&rsquo;t have any other levels. This is the reason they have? been used on the front line of the British army for the last 300 years.</p>

<p>??The French government announced yesterday that it has raised its terror ?alert level from &ldquo;Run&rdquo; to &ldquo;Hide&rdquo;. The only two higher levels in France are? &ldquo;Collaborate&rdquo; and &ldquo;Surrender.&rdquo; The rise was precipitated by a recent fire?that destroyed France&rsquo;s white flag factory, effectively paralyzing the ?country&rsquo;s military capability.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not only the French who are on a? heightened level of alert.
Italy has increased the alert level from &ldquo;Shout ?loudly and excitedly&rdquo; to &ldquo;Elaborate Military Posturing.&rdquo; Two more levels ?remain: &ldquo;Ineffective Combat Operations&rdquo; and &ldquo;Change Sides.&rdquo;?</p>

<p>?The Germans also increased their alert state from &ldquo;Disdainful Arrogance&rdquo; to?&ldquo;Dress in Uniform and Sing Marching Songs.&rdquo; They also have two higher? levels: &ldquo;Invade a Neighbour&rdquo; and &ldquo;Lose&rdquo;.?</p>

<p>?Belgians, on the other hand, are all on holiday as usual, and the only ?threat they are worried about is NATO pulling out of Brussels.</p>

<p>??The Spanish are all excited to see their new submarines ready to deploy. ?These beautifully designed subs have glass bottoms so the new Spanish navy ?can get a really good look at the old Spanish navy.??</p>

<p>Americans meanwhile and as usual are carrying out pre-emptive strikes, on?all of their allies, just in case.?</p>

<p>?And in the southern hemisphere&hellip;</p>

<p>??New Zealand has also raised its security levels &ndash; from &ldquo;baaa&rdquo; to &ldquo;BAAAA!&rdquo;. ?Due to continuing defense cutbacks (the airforce being a squadron of spotty ?teenagers flying paper aeroplanes and the navy some toy boats in the Prime?Minister&rsquo;s bath), New Zealand only has one more level of escalation, which? is &ldquo;I hope Australia will come and rescue us&rdquo;.??</p>

<p>Australia , meanwhile, has raised its security level from &ldquo;No worries&rdquo; to?&ldquo;She&rsquo;ll be right, mate&rdquo;. Three more escalation levels remain: &ldquo;Crikey!&lsquo;, "I ?think we&rsquo;ll need to cancel the barbie this weekend&rdquo; and &ldquo;The barbie is? cancelled&rdquo;. So far no situation has ever warranted use of the final? escalation level.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Found the Solar Plexus Yet?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2008/03/24/found-the-solar-plexus-yet/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-24T23:12:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.trevoke.net/blog/2008/03/24/found-the-solar-plexus-yet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have a move in a form that requires holding a hand in front of the solar plexus. One of the kids was holding his hand a little low, so I mentioned it to him.. He start hitting his chest a few times with his hand, so I laugh. &ldquo;Think you got it?&rdquo; He does it a few more times and starts coughing. &ldquo;Ah, now you got it.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
